绝命律师
第一季 第九集
翻译  西西  Liv  joy_bwl  依俊听杰
翻译  咯吱猫  心疼吉米的大白  寐兮
翻译  奶霸  ellaxinxin  喃喃  松
校对  喃喃
时间轴  梦龙  今  姜姜
后期  冈田DD萌死小新  8T  虫虫不咬人
总监  喃喃
别担心那个东西
Don't worry about that, all right?
低头看草地
Look down. Look at the grass.
像这样把鞋脱了
Kick off your shoes. Like this.
你上回这么做是什么时候
When was the last time you did that?
感觉还不错吧
Feels good, right?
是啊
Yeah.
把青草夹在脚趾间
Grass, between your toes.
感觉不错
Feels nice.
-是啊  -没错
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我在想  也许
Well, I think maybe...
我们该进去了  还有好多事要做呢
Maybe it's time we go in. We have a lot of work to do.
我们得准备好  你得准备好
We need to get ready. You need to get ready.
如果我是斯韦卡特和考科利公司
If I were Schweikart and Cokely,
我会想办法弄一张限制令
I'd seek a restraining order,
把这事变成民事骚扰问题
turn this into a civil-harassment issue.
斯韦卡特和考科利可以尽情地
Schweikart and Cokely can come after me
用限制令或别的东西来对付我
with a restraining order or anything else they got.
我会准备好的
I'll be ready.
有信心很好
Confidence is good.
有事实依据在手会更好
Facts on your side, better.
要明白自己将要面对什么
Know what you're walking into.
房子需要刷漆了
House needs a coat of paint.
所有疫苗都给它打了
I got her all her shots.
牙龈健康  没有寄生虫也没有跳蚤
Healthy gums and no worms, no fleas.
我向你保证  如果那小畜生有跳蚤
I promise you, if the little sucker has fleas,
我会亲自教训它一顿
I'll-I'll kick her butt myself.
话虽如此  但那也是条狗啊
Yeah, it's just a dog.
有只狗挺好的
Hey, it's good to have a dog around.
如果哪家养了狗
Bad guys think twice
贼进门偷东西之前还要三思呢
about breaking into a house with a dog.
是啊  这小家伙肯定能吓走不少坏人
Yeah, I bet that one's gonna keep a lot of burglars away.
随便说说而已
It's just a thought.
你可以把它养在我那里
You know, you can always k-keep it over at my place,
凯莉随时都能来看它
and Kaylee can visit her anytime she wants.
如果你决定留着它
Well, if you decide to keep her,
我车里有一大包狗粮给你
I got a giant bag of puppy chow out in the car for you--
所有宠物用品都有
all the supplies, everything you need.
好吧
All right.
你说什么
What's that?
狗可以留在这里
The dog can stay here.
你确定吗
You sure?
是的  谢谢你
Yes. Thank you.
那就好
All right. Done.
接个电话
Excuse me a minute.
喂
Yeah?
没问题
Sure.
好
Yep.
明白了
Got it.
你还好吗
Is everything okay?
挺好的  工作有消息了
Yeah, just a lead on a job opportunity.
法官大人  斯韦卡特先生和他的助手
Your honor, Mr. Schweikart and his cohorts
正设法阻止我接近被他们迫害的人
are attempting to keep me away from their victims,
-迫害吗  -是的  你不让我见我的委托人
- Victims? - My clients. Yes. You're denying me access.
哪怕是这座大楼地下室里最可恨的罪犯
Even the worst prisoners in the basement of this building
也有权见律师
are allowed access to a lawyer.
难道我可怜的老年委托人
Are you saying my poor, elderly clients
拥有的权利还不如罪犯多吗
have fewer rights than a bunch of jail inmates?
不是这个意思
Not at all,
没有人阻止麦吉尔先生见他的委托人
and no one is denying Mr. McGill access to his clients.
我们是阻止他进入养老院
We're denying him access to the property...
-这是歪曲事实  -养老院由矶鹞渡管理
- It's semantics. - Which is well within Sandpiper Crossing's rights.
那是私人财产
The building is private property.
钱可是那些老人在付
Paid for by the residents.
但管理者是有执照的专业看护人员
But managed by licensed health-aid professionals.
先生们  一次一个人
Okay, one at a time, gentlemen.
斯韦卡特先生  你为什么不让他进入养老院
Mr. Schweikart, you're denying him access on what grounds?
这些需要生活协助的老年人
These assisted-living residents
已经养成了固定的生活习惯
have a daily routine that they're used to,
而麦吉尔先生总是吵吵闹闹
and Mr. McGill, who is very loud and flamboyant,
这种行为严重影响了他们的生活
is a disturbance to these routines.
想要见律师的老年人
Residents who want to see a lawyer--
什么时候想离开都行
free to leave whenever they want.
什么叫随时离开
Leave whenever they want?
那些可是行动不便的老人
We're talking about elderly and infirm people here.
换句通俗的话说就是
The most common phrase in this place?
"我摔倒了  我起不来了"
"I've fallen, and I can't get up."
你可以提供电话咨询
There's phone consultations.
还有邮件和信使服务
There's mail and messenger services.
还有好多其他方法和委托人商谈
There's plenty of other ways to confer with clients,
但对于那些
But for residents who
不想被麦吉尔先生骚扰的人来说
don't want to be afflicted with Mr. McGill's presence,
这就属于民事骚扰案件了
This becomes an issue of civil harassment.
你还真敢把"民事骚扰"用在这里
Wow! You are stretching that definition to its limit.
你要知道  老年人爱死我了
And F.Y.I., old people adore me.
肃静  我已经了解了
Okay, I've heard enough.
我已经可以对这份限制令作出裁决了
I have enough here to let me rule on this restraining order.
太棒了
Yeah!
别担心  查克  你闻到的不是烟
Don't worry, Chuck. That's not smoke you smell.
是我
That's me.
我牛逼得快要烧起来了
This mofo is on fire.
你的老弟今天狠狠教训了斯韦卡特
Your baby bro kicked some Schweikart ass today.
这些都是什么
What the hell's all this?
你还在法庭时送来的快递
There was a delivery while you were in court.
是斯韦卡特和考科利公司送过来的吗
What, Schweikart and Cokely sent this?
是什么
What -- what is it?
他们对每一位集体诉讼代表都提出了质询
They served interrogatories on each class representative.
这一箱是作证通知
Uh, this box is deposition notices,
他们质疑我们许多老年委托人
documents calling into question the
精神方面可能有问题
mental health of many of our elderly clients,
通过证明他们并没有上诉能力
attempting to stop the class from being certified
试图阻止这次集体诉讼
on the grounds they're not competent to file.
这只是个开始
Oh, this is just the beginning.
他们还会持续地给我们送文件
They're gonna continue this document dump
直到把我们淹没为止
until we're drowning in paperwork.
好吧  我们可以处理好
All right. We can deal with this.
我是说  这个
I mean, hey, it's, uh...
都只是文书工作嘛
it's just paperwork, right?
没什么大不了的  硬着头皮上就行了
It's no big deal. Just hit it head on.
-吉米  -按优先顺序处理
- Jimmy. - Prioritize.
最重要的事情放在前面
Uh, most important stuff first.
还是先处理简单的比较好
Or is it better to, uh, deal with the easy stuff?
先把那些处理了
You know, get that off the decks.
查克  你来选
And, uh, you tell me, Chuck.
你就随便指一个箱子
I mean, you just point to a box.
我们能够做到
We can do this.
吉米  我们需要谈谈
Jimmy, we need to talk.
-查克  -先坐下吧
- Chuck. - Sit down, won't you?
没事  我还是站着吧
No, I'm good.
我知道你不喜欢听我接下来要说的话
I know you're not gonna like what I have to say next,
但是事实就是事实
but facts are facts.
我们现在所面对的  这个案件的规模
And what we're facing here, a case this size,
已经不是两个人能搞定的了
it is not a two-man job.
-我们需要帮助  -不
- We need help. - No.
为了委托人的利益
And for the good of the clients,
我们需要将这个案件委托
we need to refer this case --
别说出来
Don't say it. Don't say --
把它委托给哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
Refer it out to HHM.
该死  查克
Damn it, chuck.
不  拜托
No! Come on!
我们可以做到的  我们自己能做得很好
We can do this. We're doing great on our own.
我们不需要哈姆林或者其他人
We don't need Hamlin or anyone else.
等等
I mean, wait, hey,
我们可以像艾琳·布洛科维奇一样解决它
We can Erin Brokovich the shit out of this case.
美国律师助理  环保活动家
艾琳·布洛科维奇也不是自己做到的
Erin Brokovich didn't do it alone.
她和埃德·马斯瑞从洛杉矶找来重量级帮手
She and Ed Masry brought in heavy hitters from Los Angeles
才最终赢得了那个案件
to get that case across the goal line,
而我们现在正需要如此
and that's what we need to do.
而且那没什么丢脸的
And there's no shame in that.
这是我们的案子
This is our case!
没错  但任务异常艰巨
Yes, it's ours, and the task ahead is monumental.
我们能单独完成吗
Could we do it alone?
两人可以建起布鲁克林大桥吗
Could two men alone build the Brooklyn Bridge?
也许可以  但是得花一辈子的时间
Maybe. But it would take forever!
你觉得
Just how long do you think
矶鹞渡的住户还可以活多久
the residents of Sandpiper Crossing have?
把这个案子委托给哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
Referring this case to HHM
才真正对委托人有利
is for the good of the clients.
你以为今天你赢了  法官没有批准限制令
That argument you won today, against the restraining order?
但法官本来就不会批准的
Judge was never gonna grant that.
斯韦卡特在耍花招
Schweikart is throwing softballs,
他会不停地一个花招接着一个花招
and he's gonna keep on throwing them over and over.
我们就会一直疲于应付
And we'll be so busy swatting them away,
真正花在案子上的时间反而所剩无几
we'll never spend any time on the actual case.
这案子肯定会持续数年
This case will span years,
我俩是没有实力推动案件进展的
and we don't have the capital to carry it forward by ourselves.
根本不可能
We simply don't.
好吧
Fine.
所以
So?
把案子拿给哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
The case goes to HHM?
撒旦万岁
Hail Satan.
我向黑暗投降
I submit to the dark side.
我去给金打电话安排会面
I'll call Kim and arrange a meeting.
太好了  吉米  谢谢你
All right. Good, Jimmy. Thank you.
我知道你一定会明白这是最好的处理方式
I know you'll come to see that it's for the best.
那我得在你隔壁找间办公室了
I guess I'll have to get an office right next to yours.
总算脱离了收发室  不是吗
Finally out of the mailroom, huh?
你好
Yes. Hello.
不  是我
No, it's me.
我们是在这儿等吗
This the place where we wait?
应该是
Think so.
那么
So...
那人跟你俩说了这活儿是干嘛的吗
...what did our guy tell you about the job?
没说太多
Not much.
是个保镖的活儿  一个平民
It's a protection job. Civilian.
他相当没有经验
Guy is as green as they come,
但是我们会保证事情顺利进行
but we'll be in there to make sure things fly right.
你俩做这行很久了吧
You been doing this long?
我认为我们都是重量级人物
I-I just assume we're all heavy hitters,
这很合理  毕竟兽医只挑最好的
and it makes sense -- the vet recommends best of the best.
跟这些人种的人打交道
Dealing with some of these ethnic types,
总是会让人热血沸腾
blood tends to run a little hotter.
这是科学  生理学
That's just science. Physiology.
这是有历史先例的  你懂我的意思吧
There's historical precedent. You know what I'm saying?
你带了啥
So, what you packing?
甜椒
Uh, pimento.
啥玩意儿
Sorry, what?
甜椒三明治
Pimento sandwich.
真好笑
That's funny.
甜椒
Pimento.
我是问  你身上带了什么没有
No, I mean, what are you carrying?
你懂的  枪
You know, piece?
-什么枪  -甜椒是一种奶酪
- What's the make? - Pimento is a cheese.
它被称为南方的鱼子酱
They call it the caviar of the south.
你不想说就算了
Look, you don't want to tell me what you're carrying,
但是别把我当傻逼玩
so be it, but you don't have to be a douche about it.
我告诉你我带的东西是什么了
Just told you what I'm carrying.
所以你的意思是  你没带枪
So you're saying... you don't have a gun?
你是这个意思吗
Is that what you're saying?
你居然不带枪就来这儿了  你带了么
How are you here without a gun? You have a gun?
-带了  -当然得带
- Yeah. - Yeah. Of course.
他带着枪呢
He's got a gun.
我带了至少两把枪呢
I got at least two guns on me that I'll tell you about.
我有把老式威尔逊格斗1911
I go old school with a Wilson Combat 1911,
还有把格洛克22第三代
I got a Glock 22 gen 3,
我就只告诉你这两把
and those are just the ones I'll tell you about.
该死
I mean, what the hell?
你怎么连把枪都不带
Really, how do you not pack a gun?
你们好  我是普赖斯
Hi. Hello. Uh, my name is Pryce.
实际上  这不是我的名字
Um, actually, that's not my name.
不过我有个侄子叫普赖斯
But, uh, I have a nephew named Pryce.
我一直都挺喜欢那个名字的
I've always kind of liked that name.
不过  我们今天不是来讨论名字的
Anyway, we're not dealing with names today.
你们告不告诉我名字都行  说个假的也行
You can tell me or not tell me yours, or a fake one is fine.
如果我要跟你们说话
If I need to talk to you,
我希望最好不要以"哎  你"开头
I'd prefer something other than, "Hey, you."
总之  你们都是被强烈推荐来的  谢谢
Either way, you all come highly recommended, so thank you.
第一  我们要开很久的车
First order of business, we have a long drive ahead of us.
我车里有饮水机  还有一些饮料
I have a cooler of water in the car, some soft drinks.
我不喝咖啡  你们要喝的话转角有家餐厅
I don't drink coffee, but there is a diner on the corner.
那还有个厕所  出发之前想上厕所就去
Also a bathroom in there in case you need to go before, we go.
第二  是关于钱
Second order, uh, money.
确认一下说好的雇佣费是
Just to be clear that the agreed-upon fee
每个人五百美元  都没意见吧
of $500 per man is...agreed upon.
-如果大家都能接受的话  -我有意见
- Uh, if that's acceptable... - yeah, I have a thought.
请讲
Y-yeah?
不如给我和大个子每人七百五
How about you give me and man mountain $750 each
让糟老头走人
and send Uncle Fester there home?
他连枪都没带
He's not carrying a gun.
他就是个废物
He's useless.
他说的是真的吗  你没带枪
I-is that true? Y-you di-- you didn't bring a gun?
我不需要带枪
I didn't think I'd need one.
这可是个保镖活儿
It's a protection job.
你需要枪来保护你的雇主
It's basic common sense that you need a gun
这是基本常识
to protect your employer.
懂吗
I mean, duh!
你是我们的负担
You're dead weight.
他就是个没带枪的废物
He's just a third wheel without a piece.
听我说  我要用枪的话可以从他那儿拿一把
I'll tell you what, if I need a gun, I'll use one of his.
是吗  想用我的枪
Really? One of my guns?
怎么可能呢
How do you picture that happening, exactly?
我会直接动手拿
Well, I guess I'm gonna take it from you.
想法不错嘛
That...that is just special, huh?
"拿"  你打算怎么拿走我的枪
"Take." How are you gonna take one of my guns?
来呀来  拿走我的枪
I mean, come on, billy jack-off, take my gun from me.
让我见识见识  来  送到你跟前
Let me see it. Here. I'll make it easy for you.
不用送到我跟前
You can make it not so easy.
好啊
Sure thing.
来吧
You got it.
靠  你个王八...
What the -- son of a --
好了  看看你都有什么好货
Okay, let's see what you got.
不错嘛
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你这种人
I mean, a guy like you,
我打赌你脚踝也绑了枪  对吧
I'll bet you'd have an ankle holster, wouldn't you?
不错啊  还有什么
You know, that's cute. What else?
真是个宝贝
Now, that's impressive.
这么多枪  我都不知道选哪把好
So many guns, I don't know which one to use.
你呢  要来一把吗
How about you? You want one?
好了
All right.
我们走吧
Let's go.
可是我们需要三个人
But we need three guys.
不  不需要  来吧  走了
No. No, we don't. Come on. Let's go.
他没事
Ah, he'll be fine.
现在就剩我一个人了  那一千五都归我
And now that I'm doing the job alone, I get the full $1,500.
你没异议吧
Do we agree upon that?
当然
Sure.
你可以的  没问题
You got this, okay? No problem.
-我知道  -西装还合身吗
- Yes. - The suit okay?
-穿着紧不紧  热不热  -嗯
- Is it too tight or too hot? - Yeah.
不  我是说正合适
No, I mean -- no, no, no. It's -- it's good.
好了  你看起来很不错
Yeah, well, you look -- you look good.
根本看不出里面还套了太空服
Can't even tell that's under there.
这主意真棒
It was a good idea.
一旦你撑不住  不舒服的话
If at any point it's too much, you're uncomfortable,
我们就立马回家
we'll turn around and come home.
你要不要想个暗号
You want maybe like a safe word?
"快带我回家"怎么样
How about, "Get me the hell home"?
不错  好了  我们出发吧
That'll work. Okay. Let's do this.
出发
Let's do this.
天儿不错
Okay. Looking good.
我们就当是去兜个风
Just going for a little ride.
我来为你开车门
Here, let me get that for you.
请进
Here you go.
-吉米  -马上来
- Jimmy! - Just a sec.
我去
Aw, crap.
怎么了
What is it?
我昨晚肯定忘关机了
I must have left my stupid phone on last night.
-没电了  -你能不能把它放后备箱里
- It's dead. - Well, could you put it in the trunk?
好的
Uh, yeah.
就这样吧
Okay, then.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
收齐了吗
Is that everyone?
他马上就到
He'll be here in one minute.
还有人拿着手机吗  都放到里面
Anyone still have a phone, add it to the collection now.
-好了  关机吧  -好的  知道了
- Okay, shut it down. - Okay, got it.
你还好吧  没事儿吧
How you doing? You doing all right?
-还好  -那太好了
- Yeah, yeah. - Okay, great stuff.
好啦  迈步向前
Okay, we're walking.
进去吧  查克
Walking in, Chuck. Here we go.
见到你太好了  老朋友  欢迎回来
Good to see you, my friend. Welcome home.
霍华德  你不必这样大张旗鼓
Howard, you didn't need to do all this.
大家都情不自禁我也拦不住啊
Oh, I couldn't have stopped them if I'd wanted to.
来吧  我们上楼去
Come on. Let's get you upstairs.
好的  你好啊  法兰西斯
Yeah, sure. Hey, Francis.
布兰达
Brenda!
你刮胡子了啊
Oh, hey, you shaved.
目前为止  已经有六十八位原告
To date, we have 68 very willing plaintiffs
决意发起集体诉讼
signed to the class action
这个数字有望增加到三百五十或更多
with the hopes of raising that number to 350 or more.
还要多得多  我们现在知道
Many more now that we know
矶鹞渡在五个州都设有中心
Sandpiper has facilities in five states.
诈骗  不公平交易
Fraud, unfair and deceptive trade practices,
还有敲诈勒索
and racketeering.
天啊  这真是...
Jesus. Guys, this is...
虽然任何官司都不简单
Well, no case is ever a slam dunk,
但我从来没有对一场官司
but I feel as confident about this
有如此大的信心
as anything that's ever come through our doors.
法兰西斯  组织一队人马去州外
Francis, start putting together teams to travel out of state,
跟这些老人谈谈
talk to these residents.
把四年员工和最好的两年员工两两组队
Pair some fourths with our best second years.
劳拉来安排行程
Laura will take care of the travel arrangements.
金和丹尼尔
Kim and Daniel,
你们去见吉米签的那些委托人
take the list of clients Jimmy's signed,
代表哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所去
introduce yourself as the face of HHM.
让他们感到安全  充满自信
Make them feel secure and confident.
霍华德  你这么激动我很高兴
Hey, Howard, I'm glad you're all excited,
不过  我们可以先谈谈条件吗
but, uh, can we slow down a second and discuss terms, maybe?
当然
Oh, uh, of course.
我有点迫不及待了
Kind of shot out of a canon with this case.
你这案子太激动人心了
It's exciting stuff you have here.
我知道
Hey, I get it.
查克已经是权益合伙人了
Look, Chuck is already an equity partner,
你呢  作为把这个官司带给我们的律师
and you, as the lawyer who brought this case to the firm,
我们可以保证给你...
we can guarantee you, say...
最终和解金共同基金份额的两成
...20% of the common-fund share of the final settlement.
那还不错
That will work.
那可能得好几年时间呢
That's a few years down the road.
至于现在给你的钱
As for money for you now,
因为我们是不支付介绍费的
uh, we don't do referral fees.
查克也同意
Chuck will agree.
律所认为介绍费不道德
HHM doesn't view that as ethical.
我们讨论过的
As we discussed.
但是我们可以按你已经投入的时间
But what we could do is arrange an of-counsel fee
付给你律师费
for the time that you've already put in --
你用来立案的时间
time that you spent building the case.
我想可以付给你两万吧
I think we could go as high as $20,000.
这也不错
That, too, will work.
成交
Great.
给我一张正式发票
Give us an official invoice,
我叫海伦给你开张支票
and I'll have Helen cut you a check.
就在这儿
Oh, got it right here.
我想要312室做我的办公室
And, uh, I'd like to use 312 as an office.
就在查克办公室旁边
It's right next to Chuck's.
-不好意思  -312室
- I'm sorry? - 312.
我知道  委托人喜欢那儿的风景
I know, it's got that view that the clients love,
不过你知道吗
but you know what?
那是浪费空间啊
That's a waste of space.
厨房边的等候区就足够好了
The waiting area by the kitchen is just as good.
得了  我只要一间办公室而已
Well, come on, guys. I mean, I need an office.
你们都先出去一下
Can I have the room?
都出去一下  请给我们几分钟
Everybody, please, just give us a few.
霍华德...
Um, Howard...
等他们都走了再说  查克
When the room's clear, Chuck.
吉米...
Jimmy...
吉米  我还是直说了吧
Jimmy, I'm just gonna say it.
我们不会雇你
You're not working here.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
你说这场官司赢定了
You said this case is a slam dunk.
是的  我们想打这场官司
Yes. We want the case.
我们不想要...
Uh, we don't want, um...
我们只想要这个案子
The case is all we want.
你开什么...  你是认真的吗
You got to be -- you're serious?
我手捧白金盘子  向你奉上一个
I walk in here with a multimillion-dollar
价值数百万的集体诉讼案子
class-action lawsuit on a damn platinum platter...
案子是我发现的  诉讼也是我发起的
a-a case that I found, that I made happen,
而你居然不要我
and you don't want me?
到底为什么
W-why in Christ not?
我知道你讨厌我  霍华德
Well, I know that you hate me, Howard.
没事的
It's -- all right.
其实我也讨厌你
You better believe feeling goes both ways,
不过我愿意把私人感情撇开  跟你合作
but I'm willing to set that aside to work with you on this.
你怎么就不能跟我合作呢
Why can't you do the same for me?
到底是什么让你如此耿耿于怀
What is it that you can't let go of?
我到底如何侮辱了你优秀且正直的品行
What slight did I make to your fine, upstanding character
你竟无法原谅我
that you can't forgive?
这是我和我的合伙人大多数人的决定
A majority decision has been made by myself and the partners,
恕我冒昧  查克
all due respect to you, Chuck.
我们不会让任何新的律师加入律所
We are not taking in any new associates into the firm.
狗屁  什么新律师
Bullshit! "New associates"?!
如果别人拿着这个案子来找你
Someone walks in with a case like this,
你会求着他入伙
you beg them to be partner!
告诉我到底为什么
Tell me why!
以前你不肯要我  行  现在你也不要我吗
You didn't want me then, okay. You don't want me now?!
解释一下
Explain it.
霍华德
Howard.
我不知道该说什么
I-I don't know what to say.
我很失望
I am very disappointed.
我真的认为你该再考虑一下
I really think you should reconsider.
很抱歉  不行
I'm sorry, but no.
我认为吉米最好接受律师费
I think it's best if Jimmy takes the of-counsel fee.
我们可以多付他一些
We could probably up it a bit.
要记住  结案后你的酬劳会很高
Keep in mind, you will be well compensated in the back end.
这么好赚的钱  吉米  没理由拒绝的
It's easy money, Jimmy. No reason not to take it.
去死吧  霍华德
Go to hell, Howard.
我不会把案子给你的
I'm not giving you my case.
而且我会告诉那些委托人
And I'm gonna tell every one of those clients
你就是头满嘴谎言  卑鄙无耻的猪
what a lying, miserable pig fucker you are.
我就算把这案子毁了
I will burn the whole thing to the ground
也不会给你的
before I give it to you.
好吧  如果你意已决的话
Okay, then, if that's your decision.
祝你今后一切顺利
Good luck to you moving forward.
刚才是哪一出
What the hell just happened?
请进
Yeah, come.
你好
Hi.
你有空吗
Was wondering if you had a moment?
有  稍等一下
Sure. Just give me a second.
什么事
What's up?
我想跟你谈谈今天的事
I wanted to talk about what happened today.
矶鹞渡的案子没谈成
With Sandpiper Crossing. Things didn't work out.
很不幸
It was unfortunate.
那是个好案子  但木已成舟
It was a good case, but...things happen.
我只是想知道为什么
I'm just trying to understand why.
吉米发现了那个案子
Jimmy found that case.
他立案了  四处奔波搜集资料
He built it, did all of the legwork.
没有他就不会有这个集体诉讼
The class action doesn't exist without him.
他应该留下来工作
He deserves a seat at the table.
我明白  不过已经决定了  金...
I understand, but the decision has been made, Kim, so...
谢谢你的意见
Thank you for your input.
可是  为什么
B-- but...why?
合伙人已经做出了决定
The partners have made a decision,
至于原因跟你无关
and the "Why" is not your concern.
我觉得跟我有关
I think it is my concern.
为什么呢
And why is that?
因为他是我的朋友
Because he's my friend,
在我看来  你并没有公平对待他
and the way I see it, you're not treating him fairly.
那只是你的看法
The way you see it.
我不知道你对他有什么印象...
I don't know what image you have of him --
过去还是现在...
past or present --
或者他对你做了或说了什么
or whatever he did or said to you,
但吉米是个优秀的律师  而且他工作很努力
but Jimmy is a good lawyer and he works very hard.
是你朋友让你来跟我说这些的吗
Did your friend send you in here to say that?
不是
No.
这都是我自己的想法
I'm saying it because I believe it.
好吧  我知道了
Well, duly noted.
你知道我是怎么想的吗
Want to know what I believe?
我觉得你在这件事上管得也太宽了
I believe that you're way out of your depth in this matter.
以后你要是还想来我办公室
So, the next time that you want to come in here
指责我
and tell me what I'm doing wrong,
你最好把话留着说给自己听
you are welcome to keep it to yourself.
你的意见  我压根不在乎
Because I don't care.
等等
Stop.
把门关上
Close the door.
他们迟到了
They're late.
肯定是堵车了
Must be traffic.
等下我要怎么办
I wonder how this is supposed to work.
我是说  谁先来
I mean, who goes first?
是我先把药给他们呢
You know, do I hand over the pills first?
还是他们先给我钱  我再给他们药
Or do they give me the money and then I hand over the pills?
其实我觉得
I mean, I guess it makes sense
一手交钱一手交货才对
if we just exchanged at the same time, right?
那就公平多了
I mean, that's -- that's fair.
要不就数到三
I mean, just count to three.
你最好话少说点
Probably the less talk, the better.
是啊
Right.
我想
Yeah, I suppose --
碰到这种事情  谁都会多想
I suppose you could really over-think something like this.
是啊  无论如何...
Yeah. Well, in any case --
等下你就这么办
Here is what is going to happen.
你先问他们要钱  再数钱
You're gonna take the money. You're going to count it.
如果钱够数  就把药给他们
If it's all there, you hand them the pills.
就这么简单
Easy peasy.
我就知道得带三个人
I knew we needed three guys.
这本来就是三个人的活
I knew it. It's a three-man job.
老天
God.
你好啊
Hello. Hi.
东西带来了吗
Do you have it?
那你带...带钱了吗
Do you have -- do you have the money?
钱够吗
Is it all there?
那个  还  还少二十块
Uh, we're -- we're short $20 -- $20.
算了吧
That's fine.
把钱交齐  否则一切免谈
Agreed amount or no deal.
你说真的吗
You serious?
你觉得我故意少给你钱吗
You saying I intentionally shorted you?
当然不  犯错也是难免的
No. Mistakes happen.
就为区区二十块  连生意你都不做了吗
You're really willing to blow up this deal over 20 bucks?
那得看你做不做
Are you?
都在这儿了
It's all there.
八十毫克的药片  从没开过封
Uh, 80-milligram pills -- still factory-sealed.
现在该给我钱了吧
You can pay me now.
你...你怎么知道
So... h-how did you know?
你怎么知道不用带枪
How did you know not to bring a gun?
我就直说了  给我一千五
This $1,500 -- I'll just say it --
你这是拣了大便宜
You're getting a bargain.
来这儿之前我可是做足了功课
I put in a lot of legwork before coming here.
刚才那家伙叫伊格纳西奥·瓦尔加
Now, that fella you just met with, name is Ignacio Varga.
他和一帮毒贩一起干
He runs with a connected crew of drug dealers.
刚刚和你做的这笔生意
Now, this deal he's doing with you,
是他背着同伙做的
he's doing outside his crew.
他可不想被他老大发现
He doesn't want his bosses to know,
所以  他最怕出岔子
So it was in his best interest that things go very smoothly.
总结一下  要当罪犯  先得做点功课
The lesson is, if you're gonna be a criminal, do your homework.
等等  我可不是坏蛋
Wait. I-I'm not a bad guy.
我也没说你是坏蛋  我说你是罪犯
No, I didn't say you're a bad guy. I said you're a criminal.
有啥区别吗
What's the difference?
我见过好罪犯  坏警察
I've known good criminals and bad cops,
卑劣的牧师  高尚的小偷
bad priests, honorable thieves.
你或者守法  或者违法
You can be on one side of the law or the other,
但只要和别人做生意  就得遵守约定
but if you make a deal with somebody, you keep your word.
你这就可以拿钱回家  再也不干这种事
You can go home today with your money and never do this again,
但你到底是拿了本不属于你的东西
but you took something that wasn't yours,
还用它来卖钱
and you sold it for a profit.
所以你已经是个罪犯了  不过是好是坏
You're now a criminal -- good one, bad one?
就看你自己了
That's up to you.
我能弄到更多药
I -- I can get more pills.
那人肯定也会一直买
And I am sure that fella will keep buying.
开车回家吧
Why don't you get us home?
睡一觉再决定
You can sleep on it before you decide.
我很担心你
I was worried about you.
打了你十几通电话
I must have called a dozen times.
抱歉  我手机没电了
Sorry. My phone died.
住在查克家的一项特别待遇
It's one of the perks of living in Chuck-land --
没插座
nowhere to plug in.
但今晚在吉米家
But tonight -- it's Jimmy-land.
有杜松子酒  龙舌兰酒
I've got gin, I've got tequila,
还有上好的肯塔基波旁酒
I've got good Kentucky bourbon,
这些酒你随便挑
and you may partake with me in any beverage of your choice
只要你能听我痛骂
on one condition -- you have to listen to me rant
你老板是个不折不扣的王八蛋
about what an absolute unwashed asshole your boss is.
吉米
Jimmy.
这是事实  别为他辩白
No, nah, it's true. Don't deny it.
他已经傻逼到了
He has reached a level of douchebaggery
会遗传给后世子孙的程度
that will live on for generations --
被风语者代代相传
passed down by wind talkers and the like.
他宁愿让一个几百万的案子打水漂
He'd rather tank a multi-million-dollar case
也不愿跟我合作
than work with me.
有毛病  他脑子有病
That's -- that's sick. He has a sickness.
他这么讨厌我吗
No, he hates me that much?
我更讨厌他  你喝什么
I hate him more! What you drinking?
吉米
Jimmy.
没错  我想抓着他的针织领带
Yeah, I want to grab him by that stupid knit tie of his
把他甩飞
and swing him around.
-吉米  -"哈姆林靛蓝"
- Jimmy. - "Hamlindigo blue."
-不如叫"哈姆林舔烂我"  -吉米
- How about "Hamlindigo blow me"?! - Jimmy!
我觉得你应该接受他的条件
I think you should take the deal.
什么
What?
我觉得你该好好想一想
I think you should slow down and think about it
因为接受他的条件绝对是你最好的选择
because taking the deal really is the best thing for you.
你可以找间体面的办公室  自己的办公室
You'll find yourself a proper office -- your office.
积累实践经验
You'll build your practice.
不用理会哈姆林和他的律所
You'll leave Hamlin and HHM behind --
自己创业
be your own man.
你希望我放弃这个案子吗
You want me to give up the case?
我的案子
My case?
我希望你快乐
I want you to be happy.
我知道你放不下这个案子  但是...
And I know you want to stay with the case, but...
你可以毫无风险得到全部报酬
You'll get all the financial reward without the risk.
这能叫差吗
How can that be bad?
你来这里帮那个混蛋说话
You come here peddling that horseshit on me?
给你好处你就替他卖命是吧
God, you?! You sure know where your bread is buttered, huh?
你不愿意跟老板作对是吧
You don't want to go up against the boss. Is that it?
你简直  你简直就是他的走狗
You're like a -- you're like a damn pod person.
哈姆林答应你什么好处
What did Hamlin promise you?
别告诉我一点好处就把你收买了
Please, tell me he didn't buy you off cheap.
他承诺给你那间办公室了吗
Did he promise you the office I asked for?
还是发誓绝不把你轰下楼
Or did he just swear never to move you back downstairs?!
接受他的条件
Take the deal.
狗娘养的
Oh, son of a bitch.
吉米
Jimmy?
天  你什么时候进来的
Jesus, when did you come in?
不知道  我把表放在外面了
I don't know. I...left my watch outside.
大概一小时前来的吧
You know, maybe an hour ago.
你准备熨衣服吗
Are you doing some ironing?
没错  我...
Yeah, I...
我知道昨天事情不太顺利
Hey, I know things didn't go well for us yesterday,
但是  回办公室的感觉很不错
but, boy, being back in the office sure felt good.
相当棒
Really good.
万一我有更多活  我得做好准备
I want to be prepared in case any more work comes my way.
太空毯穿西装里面
And the space-blanket lining in the suit --
这主意真棒
what a fantastic idea.
走出家门再也不是煎熬了
It really made being outside m-much more tolerable.
待会我想在小区周围
I'm thinking about taking a little walk
散会儿步
around the block later on.
真棒  查克  你该出去转转
That's great, Chuck. You should do that.
吉米  你没事吧
Jimmy, are you all right?
我昨晚没睡
Well, I didn't sleep last night,
一直在思考
so just doing some soul searching,
我决定了
and I -- I came to a decision.
我接受哈姆林的条件
I'm gonna take that deal.
你确定
You're sure?
这是你想要的吗
This is what you want?
金找我谈了  我很生气
Kim talked to me. I got pretty nasty.
做这决定我并不自豪  但想想她说的话
I'm not proud, but thinking about what she said,
不要这笔钱我不成傻子了吗
I'd be a fool to pass up that money.
钱是不少
It is a lot of money.
我根本不想和霍华德合作
And I have zero interest in working with Howard,
所以我和他还是各做各的比较好
so it's probably best that we keep to our separate sandboxes.
希望一切顺利
Wish it could have worked out.
你能想象吗
Yeah. Imagine that, huh?
麦吉尔兄弟并肩跨入法庭大门
The two McGill boys side by side storming the gates,
弘扬正义  惩恶扬善
righting wrongs, taking down the bad guys,
而且还大把大把地赚钱
and making a boatload of money to boot.
实在是太棒了  不是吗
That would have been great, right?
最棒的
The very best.
-是啊  -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我来搞定霍华德
I'll keep on Howard.
我不会缠着他不放  但也许可以慢慢拖垮他
I won't badger him, but maybe I can gradually wear him down,
让他回心转意
You know, get him to come around.
真是  谢谢
That's -- thanks.
你真是
Wow, you...
有一个如此照顾我的哥哥真是太幸运了
I'm so lucky to have you looking out for me.
我尽量  没说一定能成
I'll do what I can. I'm not promising anything.
我懂  没那么容易
No, I get it. It's a long shot.
他可能会改变主意
Hey, he might change his mind.
是啊
Yeah.
也许你有办法
Hey, maybe there is a way
能让霍华德改变主意
that you could get Howard to change his mind.
-什么办法  -辞职
- How? - Quit.
-吉米  不行  -不  这很完美
- Jimmy, n-no. No, no, no. - No, no, it's -- it's perfect.
我们已经谈过了
We've already been through all of this,
我跟你说了我不会离开律所
all -- all the reasons I'm never gonna leave HHM.
不不  但你不是真的退出
No, no. You -- but you don't have to really quit.
你只是威胁要退出
Okay, you just threaten to quit, right?
你就跟霍华德来一场博弈
You get in a game of chicken with Howard.
他不得不让步  不然律所就会垮
He's got to blink, or HHM goes under.
这计划太棒了
It's -- it's a perfect plan.
-吉米  -如果你希望
- Jimmy -- - If that's what you want,
咱俩能一起工作
you know, u-us working together.
你可以轻而易举地实现
You can make it happen -- easily.
我是说
I mean, hey.
昨天你在律所受到的接待
That reception you got yesterday at HHM --
感觉怎么样
How about that, right?
所有人都为你鼓掌
The whole lobby of HHM applauding for you.
他们爱你
They love you!
现在你威胁要退出
Now, you threaten to pull out --
哈姆林绝对不敢惹毛你
Hamlin would be insane to screw with you.
你手上可拿着杀手锏呢
You've got the nuclear option.
一旦你按下发射键
Launch the doomsday device.
他们就玩完了
Game over --
如果你真想跟我一起工作的话
If working with me is what you really want.
怎么样  查克
Right, Chuck?
是你打电话给他
You called him.
是你打给哈姆林
You called Hamlin.
我把手机放进邮箱之前都会关机
I always turn my phone off before I put it in your mailbox.
两晚前  手机是开着的  第二天没电了
Two nights ago, it was left on -- battery drained.
而且我十分确定把它关了
And I was so damn sure that I turned it off,
因为我一直这么干
you know, 'cause I always do.
这是习惯
It's a habit, right?
所以我就在琢磨  一直在想
So, it was nagging me. It was nagging me!
所以我打给电话公司
So I called the phone company.
结果发现当晚两点有一条被删除的通话记录
Turns out, there was a deleted call at 2:00 A.M.,
那时候我就在那儿睡觉
when I was asleep right there.
你知道是打给谁的吗
And you know who's number?
哈姆林
Hamlin's.
唯一能播出这个电话
The only person who could have made that call
并删除记录的人就是你  查克
and deleted it is you, Chuck.
好家伙  打电话啊
Boy, that phone, huh?
手机对你来说应该像个酒精喷灯一样烫手啊
Phone must have felt like a blowtorch in your ear.
那些电流  还有那些在你脑边
All that electricity, all those radio waves
萦绕不去的无线电波
right up against the side of your head?
天哪
My god.
什么事这么重要
What was so important
让你在会面之前必须打给霍华德
that you had to call Howard before our meeting?
我能想到的唯一一件事  唯一说得通的
The only thing I can think, the only thing that makes sense
就是你告诉他不要雇我
is you told him not to hire me.
一直都是你  对吗
It was always you, right?
从我通过律师考试
Right back to when I passed the bar
想要加入律所开始
and tried to join the firm.
你就不想雇我
You didn't want me.
说出来
Speak up.
告诉我为什么
Tell me why.
你现在起码可以给我一个解释
It's the least you can do for me now.
我是你亲弟弟
I'm your brother.
我们应该照顾彼此的
We're supposed to look out for each other.
你为什么要跟我作对  查克
Why were you working against me, Chuck?
你不是个真正的律师
You're not a real lawyer.
什么
I'm what?
你不是个真正的律师
You're not a real lawyer!
美属萨摩亚大学  我的老天
University of American Samoa, for Christ sake?
在线学习  简直是笑话
An online course? What a joke.
我付出了多少努力才到现在的地位
I worked my ass off to get where I am,
而你走了这些捷径
and you take these shortcuts and you think,
就能变成我的同事吗
suddenly, you're my peer?
你跟我一样当律师  就因为你很幽默吗
You do what I do because you're funny
你能让别人发笑吗
and you can make people laugh?
我为这事业付出了一切
I committed my life to this.
绝对不能让你这么容易就掺和进来
You don't slide into it like a cheap pair of slippers
抢走所有的功劳
and then reap all the rewards.
我还以为你为我骄傲
I thought you were proud of me.
我确实为你骄傲
I was!
你金盆洗手后到收发室工作
When you straightened out and got a job in the mailroom,
我感到非常骄傲
I was very proud.
所以就应该那样是吗
So that's it then, right?
让老吉米待在收发室
Keep old Jimmy down in the mailroom
因为他没资格成为一名律师
'cause he's not good enough to be a lawyer.
我了解你
I know you.
我了解你的过去  你的现在
I know what you were, what you are.
人不会改变的  你是"风流吉米"
People don't change. You're slippin' Jimmy.
风流吉米我能接受
And slippin' Jimmy I can handle just fine,
但再加上一个法律学位
but slippin' Jimmy with a law degree
就像猩猩拿着一把机关枪
is like a chimp with a machine gun.
法律是神圣的
The law is sacred!
如果你滥用权力  会伤害别人的
If you abuse that power, people get hurt.
这不是一场游戏
This is not a game.
你得知道  在某种程度上
And you have to know, on -- on some level,
你也知道我是对的
I know you know I'm right.
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
我
I...
我给你买了一包二十磅的冰
I got you a 20-pound bag of ice
一些培根和鸡蛋
and some bacon and some eggs
几块你喜欢吃的牛排
and a couple of those steaks that you like
还有一些燃料罐
and some fuel cannisters.
够你用三四天的
It's enough for three or four days.
之后你就要靠自己了
After that, you're on your own.
我受够了
I am done.
吉米
Jimmy.
Jimmy!
吉米  回来
Jimmy, come back inside.
吉米
Jimmy!
Jimmy.